Hi, this is Sean Hobson and what we want to talk about right now is the proper mechanics of making a good shot.
Now, it doesn't matter if you've got all of your body form perfectly correct ready to make a shot.
The most important thing in making a good shot is you got to be facing the basket.
I don't know how many times I've seen players with the greatest shots ever, but they've chose to shoot going from the side or fading away or they shoot coming away from the basket or whatever.
The best way for you to become an accurate shooter is to have your body squared.
Now you see our player right here has good form, we've got a good base, their hands are just perfectly set and the key is right here, their shoulders.
If I took their shoulders and drew lines off their shoulders, they are facing right to the basket.
That's where we're trying to score.
So, right now you see that he's perfectly tilted toward the basket.
Now, if he takes a step down to the baseline, he takes a step down the baseline, we don't want him to shoot the ball from the shoulder coming over the top.
Instead we want him to take that step around, square his shoulders to the basket and make that shot.
Same thing here.
If Hunter's up here and he dribbles to the middle, we want him to find the basket, turn, face the basket, get his shoulders squared up and make the shot.
If you are squared, if you're facing the basket, you're going to up your chances tremendously of making that shot.